The following content is provided under a Creative
Commons license.
Your support will help MIT OpenCourseWare
continue to offer high quality educational resources for free.
To make a donation or to view additional materials
from hundreds of MIT courses, visit MIT OpenCourseWare
at ocw.mit.edu.
So today, we're going to move on
to a fairly different world than the world
we've been living in.
And this will be a world we'll be living in for quite
a few lectures.
But before I do that, I want to get back to just finish up
something that Professor Grimmsen started.
You may recall he talked about family trees.
And raised the question, was it actually possible to
represent all ancestral relationships as a tree?
Well, as a counter example, I'm sure some of you are
familiar with Oedipus Rex.
For those of you who are not, I'm happy to give you a
plot summary at the end of the lecture.
It's a rather bizarre plot.
But it was captured in a wonderful song by Tom Lair.
The short story is Oedipus ended up marrying his
mother and having four children.
And Tom Lair, if you've never heard of Tom Lair, you're
missing one of the world's funniest songwriters.
And he had a wonderful song called Oedipus Rex.
And I recommend this YouTube as a way to go and listen
to it.
You can gather from the quote what the story is about.
I also recommend the play, by the way.
It's really kind of appalling what goes on, but it's
beautiful.
All right, back to the main topic.
Here's the relevant reading.
A small bit from later in the book and then chapter 14.
You may notice that we're not actually going through the book
in order.
And the reason we're not doing that is because we're trying
to get you information you need in time to do problem
sets.
All right.
So the topic of today is really uncertainty.
And the fact that the world is really annoyingly hard to
understand, this is a signpost related to 6.0002, but we
won't go into too much detail about it.
We'd rather things were certain, but in fact, they
usually are not.
And this is a place where 6.0002 diverges from the
typical introductory computer science course, which
focuses on things that are functional.
Given an input, you always get the same output.
It's predictable.
And we like to do that because that's easier to teach.
But in fact, for reasons we'll be talking about, it's not
nearly as useful if you're trying to actually write
computations that help you understand the world, you
have to face uncertainty head on.
An analogy is for many years people believed in Newtonian
mechanics.
I guess they still do in 801 maybe.
That every effect is a cause, and Apple falls from the
tree because of gravity, and you know where it's going to
land, and the world can be understood causally.
And people believe this really for quite a long time.
Most of history, until the early part of the 20th
century, when the so-called Copenhagen doctrine was put
forth, the doctrine there from Bohr and Heisenberg, two
very famous physicists, was one of what they called
causal nondeterminism.
And their assertion was that the world, at its very
most fundamental level, behaves in a way that you
cannot predict.
It's OK to make a statement that x is highly likely to
occur, almost certain to occur.
But for no case can you make a statement x will occur.
Nothing has a probability of one.
This was hard for us to imagine today when we all know
quantum mechanics, but at the turn of the century this was
a shocking statement.
And two other very well-known physicists, Albert Einstein
and Schrodinger, basically said, no, this is wrong.
Bohr, Heisenberg, you guys are idiots.
It's just not true.
They probably didn't call them idiots.
And this is most exemplified by Einstein's famous quote
that God does not play dice, which is indicative of the
fact that this was actually a discussion that permeated not
just the world of physics, but society in general.
People really turned it into literally a religious issue,
as did Einstein.
Well, so now we should ask the question, does it
really matter?
And to illustrate that, I need two coins.
I forgot to bring any coins with me.
Anyone got a coin they can lend me?
All right.
Now, this is where I see how much the students trust me.
Do I get a penny?
Do I get a silver dollar?
All right, so what have we got here?
All right, this is someone who's entrusting me with two
quarters, not so bad.
So we'll take these two quarters, and we'll shake
them up, and we'll put them down on the table.
And now we'll ask a question.
Do we have two heads, two tails, or one head and one tail?
So who thinks we have two heads?
Who thinks we have two tails?
Who thinks we have one of each?
All right, well, clearly everyone except a few people,
for example, the Indians fan, who clearly believe in the
counterfactual, made the most probabilistic decision.
But in fact, there's no nondeterminism here.
I know the answer, right?
And so in some sense, it doesn't matter whether it's
deterministic, because in fact, it's not causally
nondeterministic.
The answer is quite clear.
But you don't know the answer.
And so whether or not the world is inherently
unpredictable, the fact that we never have complete
knowledge of the world suggests that we minus well
treat it as inherently unpredictable.
And so this is called predictive nondeterminism.
And this really is what's going to underline pretty much
everything else we're going to be doing here.
All right, no comments about that?
All right, I wouldn't do that to you.
Thank you.
I know you were wishing to get an interest on the money,
but you don't get any.
All right.
What was that?
So when we think about nondeterminism in
computation, we use the words stochastic process.
And that's any process that's ongoing in which the
next state depends upon the previous states in some
random element.
So typically, up till now, when we've written code, what
one line of code did depended only on what the previous
lines of code did.
There was no randomness.
Here we're going to have randomness.
And we can see the difference if we look at these
two specifications of rolling a die.
The first one returns an int between 1 and 6 is what
I'll call underdetermined.
By that, I mean you can't tell what it's going to return.
Maybe it will return a different number each time you
call it, but it's not required to.
Maybe it will return 3 every time you call it.
The second specification requires randomness.
It says it returns a randomly chosen int, so it
requires a stochastic implementation.
All right, let's look at how we implement a
random process in Python.
We start by importing the library random.
This is not to say you can import any random
library you want.
It's to say you import the library called random.
Let me get my pen out of here.
And we'll use that a lot.
And then we're going to use the function in random
called random.choice.
It takes as an argument a sequence, in this case a
list, and randomly chooses one member of the list.
And it chooses it uniformly.
It's a uniform distribution.
And what that means is that it's equally probable that it
will choose any number in that list each time you call it.
We'll later look at distributions that are
not uniform, not equally probable, where
things are weighted.
But here it's quite simple.
It's just uniform.
And then we can test it using test roll.
Take some number of n and rolls the die that many times
and creates a string telling us what we got.
So let's consider running this on, say, test roll of five.
And we'll ask the question, if we run it, how probable is
it that it's going to return a string of five ones?
How do we do that?
Now I know how many people here are either in 6041 or have
taken 6041?
Raise your hand.
Oh, good.
So very few of you know probability.
That helps.
All right, so how do we think about that question?
Well, probability, to me at least, is all about
counting, especially discrete probability, which is what
we're looking at here.
What you do is you start by counting the number of
events that have the property of interest and the number of
possible events and divide one by the other.
So if we think about rolling a die five times, we can
enumerate all of the possible outcomes of five rolls.
So if we look at that, what are the outcomes?
Well, I could get five ones.
I could get five ones, four ones and a two, or four ones
and a three, skip a few.
The next one would be three ones, a two and a one, and a
two and a two, and finally, at the end, all sixes.
So remember we looked before at when we were looking at
optimization problems about binary numbers, and we said we
could look at all the possible choices of items in the
knapsack by vector of zeros and ones.
We said how many possible choices are there?
Well, it depended on how many binary numbers you could get
in that number of digits.
Well, here we're doing the same thing, but instead of
base two, it's base six.
And so the number of possible outcomes of five rolls is
quite high.
How many of those are five ones?
Only one of them, right?
So in order to get the probability of five ones, I
divide one by six to the fifth.
Does that make sense to everybody?
So in fact, we see it's highly unlikely.
Probability of five runs is quite small.
Now, suppose we were to ask about the probability of
something else.
Instead of five ones, say five, three, four, two, one, it
kind of looks more likely than that than five ones in a row.
But of course it isn't, right?
Any specific combination is equally probable.
And there are a lot of them.
So all the probability we're going to think about, we
could think about this way as simply a matter of
counting, the number of possible events, the number of
events that have the property of interest, in this case
being all ones, and then simple division.
Given that framework, there are three basic facts about
probability we're going to be using a lot of.
So one, probabilities always range from zero to one.
How do we know that?
Well, we've got a fraction, right?
And the denominator is all possible events.
The numerator is the subset of that that's of interest.
So it has to range from zero to the denominator, and that
tells us that the fraction has to range from zero to one.
So one says it's always going to happen zero, never.
So if the probability of event occurring is p, what's
the probability of it not occurring?
This follows from the first bullet.
It's simply going to be one minus p.
This is a trick that we'll find we use a lot because it's
often the case when you want to compute the probability of
something happening.
It's easier to compute the probability if it's not
happening and subtract it from one.
And we'll see an example of that later today.
Now here's the biggie.
When events are independent of each other, the probability
of all of the events occurring is equal to the
product of the probabilities of each of the events occurring.
So if the probability of A is 0.5 and the probability of
B is 0.4, the probability of A and B is what?
0.5 times 0.4.
You guys can figure that out.
I think it's 0.2.
So you'd expect that, right, that it should be much smaller
than either of the first two probabilities.
This is the most common rule at something we use all the
time in probabilities, the so-called
multiplicative law.
We have to be careful about it, however, in that it
only holds if the events are actually independent.
Two events are independent if the outcome of one has no
influence in the outcome of the other.
So when we roll the die, we assume that the first roll,
the outcome was independent of the second roll was
independent of the first roll, independent of the fourth roll.
When we looked at the two coins, we assumed that heads
and tails of each coin was independent
of the other coin.
I didn't, for example, look at one coin and make sure
that the other one was different.
The danger here is that people often compute probabilities
assuming independence when you don't actually
have independence.
So let's look at an example.
For those of you familiar with American football, the
New England Patriots and the Denver Broncos are two
prominent teams.
And let's look at computing the probability of whether
one of them will lose on a given Sunday.
So the Patriots have a winning percentage of 7 of 8.
They've won seven of their eight games so far, and the
Broncos six of eight.
The probability of both winning next Sunday, assuming
that this is indicative of how good they are, we can get
with the multiplicative rule.
So it's 7 over 8 times 6 over 8 or 42 over 64.
We could simplify that fraction, I suppose.
All right, does that make sense?
So this is probably a pretty good estimate of both of them
winning next Sunday.
So the probability of at least one of them losing is 1
minus that.
So here's an example of why we often use the 1 minus rule.
Because we could compute the probability of both of them
winning by simply multiplying.
And we subtract that from 1.
However, what about Sunday, December 18th?
What's the probability?
Well, as it happens, that day the Patriots are playing
the Broncos.
So now suddenly the outcomes are not independent.
The probability of one of them losing is influenced by the
probability of the other winning.
Right?
So you would expect the probability of one of them
losing is much closer to 1 than 22 over 64, which is
about a third.
So in this case it's easy, but as we'll see as we get
through the term, there are lots of cases where you have
to work pretty hard to understand whether or not two
events really are independent.
And if you get it wrong, you get a totally bogus answer.
A third versus one is a pretty big difference.
By the way, as it happens, the probability of the
Broncos losing is about 1.
All right, let's go look at some code.
And we'll go back to our dice, because it's much easier
to simulate dice games than it is to simulate
football games.
So here it is, and we're going to talk a lot about
simulations.
So here rather than rolling the die, I've
written a program to do it.
We've already seen the code for rolling a die.
And so to run the simulation, typically what we're
doing here is I'm giving you the goal.
For example, are we going to get five ones?
The number of trials, each trial in this case will be, say,
of length five.
So I'm going to roll the same die 5 times, say, 1,000
different times.
And then just some text as to what I'm going to print.
Almost all the simulations we look at are going to start
with lines that look a lot like that.
We're going to initialize some variable, and then we're
going to run some number of trials.
So in this case, we're going to get from the length of the
goal, so if the goal is five ones, then we're going to
roll the die five times.
If it's 10 runs, we'll roll the die 10 times.
So this is essentially one trial, one attempt, right?
And then we'll check the result.
And if it has the property we want, in this case, it's
equal to the goal, then we're going to increment the total,
which we initialized up here, by one.
So we'll keep track, which is just the counting.
The number of trials that actually meet the goal.
And then when we're done, what we're going to do is
divide the number that met the goal by the number of trials.
Exactly the counting argument we just looked at, and then
we'll print the result.
Almost every simulation we look at is going to have this
structure.
But be an outer loop, which is the number of trials, and
then inside, maybe we'll have a loop, or maybe it won't,
will be a single trial.
We'll sum up the results, and then we'll divide by the
number of trials.
All right, let's run it.
All right.
So a couple of things are going to go on here.
If you look at the code, as we've looked at it before,
what you're seeing is I'm computing the estimated
probability by the simulation, and I'm comparing it to the
actual probability, which we've already seen how to compute.
So if you look at it, there are a couple of things to
look at.
The estimated probability is pretty close to the actual
probability, but not the same.
Let's go back to the PowerPoint.
Here are the results.
And there are at least two question ways by this result.
First of all, how did I know that this is what would get
printed?
Remember, this is random.
How did I know that the estimate, well, there's
nothing random of the actual probability, but how did I
know that the estimated probability would be zero?
And why did it print it twice?
Because I messed up the PowerPoint, anyway.
So how do I know what would get printed?
Well, a confession.
Random.choice is not actually random.
In fact, nothing we can do in a computer is
actually random.
You can prove that it's impossible to build a computer
that actually generates truly random numbers.
What they do instead is generate numbers that are
called pseudorandom.
How do they do that?
They have an algorithm that, given one number, generates
the next number in a sequence.
And they start that algorithm with a seed.
Now, typically, they get that seed by reading the clock of
the computer.
So most computers have a clock that, say, keeps track of the
number of microseconds since January 1, 1978.
I don't know if that's still true.
That's what UNIX used to do.
So the notion is, you start your program, there's no
way of knowing how many microseconds have elapsed.
And so you're getting a random number to start the process.
Since you don't know where it starts, you don't know what
the second number is, you don't know what the third
number is, you don't know what the fourth number is.
And so it's predictably nondeterministic, because
you don't know what the seed is going to be.
Now, you can imagine that this makes programs really
hard to debug.
Every time you run it, something different could happen.
Now, we'll see often you want them to be unpredictable.
But for now, we want them to be predictable.
Makes it easier to prepare a PowerPoint.
So what you have, if we go is a command, you can call
random.seed and give it a value and say, I don't want
you to just choose some random seed.
I want you to use zero as the seed.
For the same seed, you always get the same sequence
of random values.
And so what I've done is I've set the seed to be, I think,
zero in this case.
Not because there's anything magic about zero.
It's just sort of habit.
But it made it predictable.
As you write programs with randomness in, and when
you're debugging it, you will almost surely want to start
by setting random.seed to a value.
So you get the same answer.
But make sure you debug it with more than one value
of this, so you didn't just get lucky with your seed.
All right.
So that's how I knew what would get printed.
The next question is, why did the simulation
give me the wrong answer?
The actual probability is 3 zeros and 1, 2, 8, 6.
But it estimated the probability of zero.
Why is it wrong?
Well, let's think about this.
I ran 1,000 trials.
What does it mean to say the probability is zero?
It means it tried it 1,000 times and didn't ever
get a sequence of 5 ones.
So the numerator of the division at the bottom was zero.
Hence, the answer is zero.
Is this surprising?
Well, no.
Because if that's the actual probability of getting 5 ones,
it's not very shocking that in 1,000 trials it never
happened.
Now, it's not a surprising result.
And so we have to be careful when we run these things
to understand the difference between what's, in this case,
an actual probability and what statisticians call
a sample probability.
So what we got with the sample was zero.
So what's the obvious thing to do?
If you're doing a simulation of an event
and the event is pretty rare, you
want to try it on a very large number of trials.
So let's go back to our code.
And we'll change it to, instead of 1,000, a million.
You can see up here, by the way, where I set their seed.
Now let's run it.
We did a lot better.
If we look at here, our estimated probability,
it's 3,0128, still not quite the actual probability,
but darn close.
And maybe if I'd done 10 million, it
would have been even closer.
So if you're writing a simulation to compute
the probability of an event and the event is moderately rare,
then you better run a lot of trials
before you believe your estimated probability.
In a week or so, we'll actually look at that more
mathematically and say, what is a lot?
How do we know what is enough?
All right.
What are the morals here?
Moral one, I've just told you, takes a lot of trials
to get a good estimate of the frequency of a rare event.
Moral two, we should always, if we're getting an
estimated probability, know that and probably say that
and not confuse it with the actual probability.
The third moral here is it was kind of stupid to do a simulation
since it was a very simple closed form answer
that we could compute that would really tell us
what the actual probability is.
Why even bother with the simulation?
Well, we're going to see why now because simulations can
be very useful.
Let's look at another problem.
This is the famous birthday problem.
Some of you have seen it.
What's the probability of at least two people in a group
having the same birthday?
There's a URL at the bottom that's pointing to a Google form.
I'd like, please, all of you have a computing device
to go to it and fill out your birthday.
It's anonymous, so we won't know how old you are.
Don't worry.
Actually, it's only the date.
It's not the year.
All right.
So suppose there were 367 people in the group, roughly the
number of people who took the 60001600 midterm.
If there are 367 people, what's the probability of at
least two of them sharing a birthday?
One, by something called the pigeonhole principle.
You've got some number of holes, and if you have
more pigeons than holes, two pigeons have to share a hole.
What about smaller numbers?
Well, if we make a simplifying assumption that each birth
date is equally likely, then there's actually a nice
closed form solution for it.
Again, this is a question where it's easier to compute
the opposite of what you're trying to do when subtract
it from 1.
And so this fraction is giving the probability of two
people not sharing a birthday.
The proof that this is right is a little bit elaborate, but
you can trust me, it's accurate.
But it's a formula, and it's not that complicated a
formula, though numbers like 366 factorial are big.
All right.
So let's approximate a solution.
We'll write a simulation and see if we get the same answer
that that formula gave us.
So here's the code for that.
Two arguments, the number of people in the group and the
number that we asking do they have the same birthday.
So since I'm assuming for now that every birthday is
equally likely, the possible dates range from
1 to 366 because some years have a February 29th.
I'll keep track of the number of people born in each date by
starting with none.
And then for p in the range of number of people, I'll make a
random choice of the possible dates and increment that
element of the list by 1.
And then at the end we can say look at the maximum
number of birthdays and see if it's greater than or
equal to the number of same.
So that tells us that.
And then we can actually look at the birthday problem, the
number of people, the number of same, and as usual the number
of trials.
So number of hits is 0 for t in range number of trials.
If same date is true, then we'll increment the number of
hints by 1 and then as usual divide by the number of trials.
And we'll try it for people in 10, 20, 40, and 100 people.
And then just we'll print the estimated probability and the
actual probability computed using that formula I showed
you.
I've not shown you, but I've imported a library called
math because it is a factorial implementation that's
way faster than the recursive one that we've seen before.
All right, let's run it and we'll see what we get.
So for 10 the estimated probability is 0.11.
So as you can see the estimates are really pretty good.
Once again we have this business that for 100 we're
estimating 1 when the real answer is 0.
Many, many, many nines.
But again, this is sample probability, just means in the
number of trials we did, every one for 100 people there was a
shared birthday.
This is a number that usually surprises people as to why with
100 people the probability is so high.
But we could work out the formula and see it.
And as you can see the estimates are pretty
good from my simulation.
All right, now we're going to see why we did a simulation in
the first place.
Suppose we want the probability of three people
sharing a birthday instead of two.
It's pretty easy to see how we change the simulation.
I even made it a parameter.
I just changed the number two to a number three.
The math, on the other hand, is ugly.
Why is the math so much uglier for three than for two?
Because for two, the complementary problem, the
number we're subtracting from one, is simply the question of
are all birthdays different?
So did two people share a birthday?
Is one minus or does everybody have a different birthday?
On the other hand, for three people, the complementary
problem is a complicated disjunct, a bunch of ores.
Either all birthdays are distinct, or two people share a
birthday and the rest are distinct, or there are two
groups of two people sharing a birthday and
everything is distinct.
So you can see here there's a lot of possibilities.
And so it's one minus now a very complicated formula.
And in fact, if you try and look how to do this, most
people will tell you don't bother, here's kind of a
good approximation.
But the math gets very hairy.
In contrast, changing the simulation is dead easy.
We can do that.
So if we come over here for the code, all I have to do is
change this 2 to a 3.
And I'm going to leave in this code, which is the
wrong code, computing the actual probability now for two
people sharing rather than 3.
Because I want to make it easy for you to see the
difference between what happens when we look at 3
shared rather than 2 shared.
And I get invalid syntax.
That's not good.
That's what happens when I type in real time.
Why do I have invalid syntax?
Pardon?
One person at Anna.
Oh, that's not a good line.
So now we see that if we get, say, to n equals 100, for 2
you'll remember it was 0.99.
But for 3 it's only 0.63.
So we see going from 2 sharing to 3 sharing gets us a
radically different answer.
Not surprisingly.
But we also, and the real thing I wanted you to see is
how easy it was to answer this question to the
simulation.
And that's a primary reason we use simulations to get
probabilistic questions rather than sitting down in the
pencil and paper and doing fancy probability
calculations.
Because it's often way easier to do a simulation.
We can see that in spades if we look at the next question.
Let's think about this assumption that all birthdays
are equally likely.
Well, as you can see, this is a chart of how common
birth dates are in the US, a heat map.
And you'll see, for example, that February 29th is quite an
uncommon birthday.
So we should probably treat that differently.
Somewhat surprisingly, you'll see that July 4th is a
very uncommon birthday as well.
It's easy to understand why February 29th.
The only thing I can figure out for July 4th is
obstetricians don't like working on holidays.
And so they induce labor sometime around the second or
so to the third, so they don't have to come to work on the
fourth to the fifth.
Sounds a horrible thought, but I can't think of any other
explanation for this anomaly.
Probably if you look at it, see Christmas Day is not so
common either.
So now the question, which we can answer, since you've
all filled out this form, is how exceptional are MIT
students?
We like to think that you're different in every respect.
So are your birthdays distributed differently than
other dates?
Have we got that data?
All right, so now we'll go look at that.
We should have a heat map for you guys.
This one.
Yeah.
All right, so here it is.
And we can see that they don't seem to be banded quite
as much in the summer months, probably says more about
your parents than it does about you.
But you can see that indeed we do have, wow, we have a
day where there are five birthdays that look like,
or no.
Wow.
You want to raise your hand if you're born on
February 12th?
All right, so you are exceptional that you lie
about when you're born.
But if you hadn't lied, I think we would have still
seen the probabilities would hold.
How many people were there, do we know?
146 people, 112 unique birthdays.
So indeed, the probability does work.
OK, so we know you're exceptional in a funny way.
Well, you can imagine how hard it would be to adjust
the analytic model to account for a weird
distribution of birth dates.
But again, adjusting the simulation model is easy.
I could have gone back to that heat map I showed you of
birthdays in the US and gotten a separate probability for
each day, but I was too lazy.
And instead what I observed was that we had this a few
days, like February 29th, highly unlikely.
And this band in the middle of people who were conceived in
the late fall and early winter.
So what I did is I duplicated some dates.
So the 58th day of the year, February 29th, occurs only
once.
The dates before that, I said let's pretend they occur
four times.
What only matters here is not how often they occur, but the
relative frequency.
And then the dates after that occur four times, except for
the dates in that band, which is going to have occur yet
more often.
So now, and don't worry about the exact details here, but
what I'm doing is simply adjusting the simulation to
change the probability of each date getting chosen by same
date.
And then I can run the simulation model.
And again, with a very small change to code, I've modeled
something that's mathematically enormously complex.
I have no idea to actually do this
probability mathematically.
But the code is, as you can see, quite straightforward.
So let's go to that here.
So what I'm going to do is comment this one out and
uncomment this more complicated set of dates and see
what we get.
And again, it changes quite dramatically.
You might remember before it was around, I think, 0.6
something for 100, and now it's 0.75.
So getting away from the notion that birthdays are
uniformly distributed to saying some birthdays are more
common than others, again, dramatically
changes the answer.
And we can easily look at that.
So that gets us to the big topic of simulation models.
It's a program that describes a computation that provides
information about the possible behaviors of a system.
I say possible behaviors because I'm particularly
interested in stochastic systems.
They're descriptive, not prescriptive, in the sense that
they describe the possible outcomes.
They don't tell you how to achieve a possible outcomes.
This is different from what we looked at earlier in the
course, where we looked at optimization models.
So an optimization model is prescriptive.
It tells you how to achieve an effect, how to get the
most value out of your knapsack, how to find the
shortest path from A to B in a graph.
In contrast, a simulation model says, if I do this,
here's what happens.
It doesn't tell you how to make something happen.
So it's very different, and it's why we need both.
Why we need optimization models and
we need simulation models.
We have to remember that a simulation model is only in
approximation to reality.
I put in an approximation to the distribution of birth
dates, but it wasn't quite right.
And as the very famous statistician George
Bach said, all models are wrong, but some
are actually very useful.
In the next lecture, we'll look at a useful class of
models.
When do we use simulations?
Typically, as we've just shown, to model systems
that are mathematically intractable, like the birthday
problem we just looked at, in other situations to extract
intermediate results, something that happens along
the way to the answer.
And as I hope you've seen, that simulations are used
because we can play what if games by
successively refining it.
We started with a simple simulation that assumed that
we only asked the question of, did two people share a
birthday?
We showed how we could change it to ask to three people
share a birthday.
We then saw that we could change it to assume a
different distribution of birth dates in the group.
And so we can start with something simple and we
get it ever more complex to answer questions what if.
We're going to start in the next lecture by
producing a simulation of a random walk.
And with that, I'll stop and see you guys soon.